Seidenberg, Jacob Additional Arbitration Files 5756
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
1980-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5756
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Records.
3123925
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, January 22, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 16, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5194: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Seidenberg, Jacob.
3123925
- Allied Chem. Corp; Allis Chalmers Corp; Aluma Systems Inc; Atchison, Topeka, & Santa Fe Railway Co.. (Box 1)
  - Allied Fibers and Plastics Company, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Bound
  - Allied Workers Local Union 101, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allis-Chalmers and IAMAW District, 98 Local 1400 (folder 1 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allis-Chalmers and IAMAW District, 98 Local 1400 (folder 1 of 2), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aluma Systems - Local 639, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 1 of 7), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 2 of 7), 1975-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 3 of 7), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 4 of 7), 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 5 of 7), 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 6 of 7), 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Co. (folder 7 of 7), 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Baltimore & Ohio, Newburgh & South Shore Rail Co's; Boston & Maine Corp.. (Box 2)
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, Newburgh and South Shore Railway Company (folder 1 of 4), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, Newburgh and South Shore Railway Company (folder 2 of 4), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, Newburgh and South Shore Railway Company (folder 3 of 4), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company, Newburgh and South Shore Railway Company (folder 4 of 4), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 1 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 2 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 3 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 4 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 5 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 6 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 7 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 8 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 9 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 10 of 13) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Employee's Rebuttal
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 11 of 13), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 12 of 13), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Boston & Maine Corp. (continued); Capitol Air Inc.; Conrail; Consolidated Rail Corp.. (Box 3)
  - Board of Arbitration no.387: Boston and Maine Corp. and United Transportation Union (folder 13 of 13), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Capital (International) Air, Inc., 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 1 of 11), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 2 of 11), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 3 of 11), 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 4 of 11), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 5 of 11), 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 6 of 11), 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Consolidated Rail Corp; Cuxahoga Valley RR Co; Delaware & Hudson Rwy (?) Corp; Frontier Airlines Inc; General Services Administration; Georgetown U; Gerber Products. (Box 4)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 7 of 11), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Submission of Dispute
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 8 of 11), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 9 of 11), 1977-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 10 of 11), 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.2037 Comrail and BRAC (folder 11 of 11), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.2635 Cuyahoga Valley RR Co., 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Public Law Board no.3806, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Frontier Airlines, Inc., 1980-1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Services Administration and American Federation of Government Employees, Council 236 (folder 1 of 4), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General Services Administration and American Federation of Government Employees, Council 236 (folder 2 of 4), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Services Administration and American Federation of Government Employees, Council 236 (folder 3 of 4), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Services Administration and American Federation of Government Employees, Council 236 (folder 4 of 4), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Georgetown, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Gerber Products UFCW, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Harrob's (?) Marina; Illinois Central Gulf RR; Kaiser-Georgetown Comm. (?) Health (?) Plan, Inc; Long Island RR. (Box 5)
  - Harrah's Marina, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Illinois Central Gulf RR (folder 1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Illinois Central Gulf RR (folder 2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Kaiser-Georgetown Comm. Health Plan, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mutual Benefit Joint Trust Fund (folder 1 of 3), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mutual Benefit Joint Trust Fund (folder 2 of 3), 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Long Island Railroad Company, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mutual Benefit Joint Trust Fund (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- LIRR; Louisville Gas & Electric Co; Metropolitan Police Dept, Wash. DC; Missouri, Kansas, Texas RR Co.. (Box 6)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Public Law Board no.1660 (folder 1 of 2), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.1660 (folder 2 of 2), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Vol. 3
  - Louisville Gas and Electric Co., 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - DC Metropolitan Dept. - FOP, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - UTU vs. Missouri-Kansas-Texas RR Company (folder 1 of 3), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - UTU vs. Missouri-Kansas-Texas RR Company (folder 2 of 3), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - UTU vs. Missouri-Kansas-Texas RR Company (folder 3 of 3), 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Public Law Board no.3441, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Quaker City Motor Parts; Robertshaw Controls Co.; Ryder/PIE Nationwide, Inc; Southern Pacific. (Box 7)
  - Robertshaw Controls Company USWA FMCS 84 K 20531, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ryder/Pie Nationwide, Inc. Teamster Local 992, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Work Performance Log (folder 1 of 2), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Work Performance Log (folder 2 of 2), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 1 of 14), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 2 of 14), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 3 of 14), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 4 of 14), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 5 of 14), 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 6 of 14), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 7 of 14), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 8 of 14), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 9 of 14), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Southern Pacific. (Box 8)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 10 of 14), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 11 of 14), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 12 of 14), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 13 of 14), 1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.3604: Southern Pacific Transportation Co. and BLE (folder 14 of 14), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Board no.449, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Sunray drugs (Penney drugs); Union Pacific. (Box 9)
  - Sun Ray Drugs and Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union Local 1034, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Public Law Board no.3243 (folder 1 of 3), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.3574, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.3243 (folder 2 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.3243 (folder 1 of 3), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.2938, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Union Pacific. (Box 10)
  - Public Law Board no.2938 and no.3612, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 1 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 2 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 3 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.2938, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 4 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 5 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 6 of 8), 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 7 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Public Law Board no.3728 (folder 8 of 8), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Public Law Board no.3612, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 1 of 6), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 2 of 6), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 3 of 6), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 4 of 6), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 5 of 6), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Social Security Administration Grievance File EG-42-82 (folderr 6 of 6), 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    Proposal to Remove
- 11 US Dept. of Health and Human Services; US Postal Service; Washington Gas Light Co; Washington Hospital Center; Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. (Box 11)
  - U.S. Postal Service and American Postal Workers Union, AFL-CIO (folder 1 of 2), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Postal Service and American Postal Workers Union, AFL-CIO (folder 2 of 2), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - International Union of Gas Workers Grievance, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Washington Gas Light Company and OPEIU Local 2, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - International Union of Gas Workers Grievance (folder 1 of 4), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - International Union of Gas Workers Grievance (folder 2 of 4), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - International Union of Gas Workers Grievance (folder 3 of 4), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - International Union of Gas Workers Grievance (folder 4 of 4), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Washington Gas Light Co., 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Washington Hospital Center, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - FMCS 83k 28184: Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and Amalgamated Transit Union Local 689 (folder 1 of 3), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - FMCS 83k 28184: Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and Amalgamated Transit Union Local 689 (folder 2 of 3), 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - FMCS 83k 28184: Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and Amalgamated Transit Union Local 689 (folder 3 of 3), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- WJLA TV; Western Pacific; Misc.. (Box 12)
  - Organization's Submission to Arbitration Board no.449, 1971-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - George Meany Center for Labor Studies, 1980-1984 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Public Law Board no.1348: Western Pacific RR and UTU (folder 1 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Public Law Board no.1348: Western Pacific RR and UTU (folder 2 of 4), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Public Law Board no.1348: Western Pacific RR and UTU (folder 3 of 4), 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Public Law Board no.1348: Western Pacific RR and UTU (folder 4 of 4), 1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - NABET, Local 31 and WJLA-TV Grievance No.: WJ-82-4 (folder 1 of 2), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - NABET, Local 31 and WJLA-TV Grievance No.: WJ-82-4 (folder 2 of 2), 1984 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Jacob Seidenburg, Esq. 6318 Cavalier Corridor Falls Church. VA 22044 (Box 12, Folder 9)